<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title></title>
		<description>Andrea Iuliano, Computer Science Engineer</description>
		<link>/</link>
		<atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Bitcoin Miners Visualization</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;This is an university project develop for the course &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dia.uniroma3.it/~infovis/&quot;&gt;Information Visualization&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;
The purpose of this project is to visualize the bitcoin’s miners interactions. A miner is a particular user who collaborate in the building of bitcoin blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do this we chose to develope two types of visualization, due to the different time range considered. &lt;br /&gt;
Both of them are represented by a graph view, in particular:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;macro-level interaction: it's possible to view the interactions between miners over the time. In particular it is possible to view miners that collaborated in the same blocks. So a node indicates a miner and a link means a collaboration between two miners.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;micro-level interaction: it's possible to view which blocks are mined by a miner. In this chart there are two types of node: the red one indicates a miner and the green one a block. A link between them indicates that the particular miner mined that block. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also we provided five filters to reduce the huge amount of informations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project is dived into two foldier:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Preprocessing: a parser of bitcoind's data written in Python. This module read the entire database and persist the filtered information into our mongoDB database.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Visualization: a web-app that provide the visualization service described before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!-- Contributors --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;tag_box list-unstyled list-inline&quot;&gt;
	  &lt;li&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-users fa-lg&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://v1ll0.github.io&quot;&gt;
				&lt;span&gt;Valerio Cestarelli&lt;/span&gt;
			&lt;/a&gt;
	  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>/university/2014/07/29/bitcoin.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/university/2014/07/29/bitcoin.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>BOLD</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;This is an university project develop for the course &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dia.uniroma3.it/~torlone/bigdata/&quot;&gt;Big Data&lt;/a&gt;. The purpose of this project is to perform an analysis of DNA subsequences samples, named barcode, with the aim to classify and predict the species bolonging from a specific genomic sequence. In particular we conducted an analysis based on the concept of multi-locus, comparating the results with the past mono-locus research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work was based on the data presents in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boldsystems.org/&quot;&gt;BOLD database&lt;/a&gt;. Specifically we considered species related to the family of plants and fungi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tool was realized by the combination of several components, develop by Bash Scripting and Python languages, along with a map-reduce stage.
To use it, put the data in a foldier named “data” and start “fastaSplitter.sh” from a bash terminal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More detailed information about the project can be found on this &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/pdf/relazione_bold.pdf&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; (located in italian)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Contributors --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;tag_box list-unstyled list-inline&quot;&gt;
	  &lt;li&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-users fa-lg&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://v1ll0.github.io&quot;&gt;
				&lt;span&gt;Valerio Cestarelli&lt;/span&gt;
			&lt;/a&gt;
	  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>/university/2014/07/19/bold.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/university/2014/07/19/bold.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Tetris</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;A simple Tetris game for Android devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project resulted from the challenge to realize a simple game without any game framework. Logic, multi-threading and canvas update are managed manually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-4&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-4&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tetris/screen.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>/personal/2014/06/15/tetris.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/personal/2014/06/15/tetris.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Manga Downloader</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;MangaDownlader is a simple Java automatic tool to download manga from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mangaeden.com/&quot;&gt;MangaEden&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project resulted from the need to download a lot of mangas and it was a Java experiment with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt; 
	&lt;li&gt;Multithreading programming&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Swing GUI library&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;HTML parsing with [jsoup] library&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;functionality&quot;&gt;Functionality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MangaDownloader can download an entire manga or resume a previously download. It is helpfull when the manga is not over and a new chapter is released.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every manga is stored in a foldier in your file system, which is divided into many foldiers as there are chapters (each chapter is downloaded in multithreading).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also Ubuntu user can use a bash scripts, located in extractPdfFromJPGs, to extract a pdf from the downloaded images. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-use-it&quot;&gt;How to Use it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To use it just follow the instructions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;download-the-manga&quot;&gt;Download the Manga&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mangaeden.com/&quot;&gt;MangaEden&lt;/a&gt; and select a manga from the list (you have to find a page similar to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mangaeden.com/en-manga/naruto/&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt;). When you find it, just copy the url.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run mangaedenDownloader.jar on your system &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select “Full Download” or “Resume Download”, according to the needs, and complete the fields as request.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Press “Start” and wait until it has finished.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;pdf-extraction&quot;&gt;PDF Extraction&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These project contains two scripts: “extractPdf.sh” and “mangaToPDF.sh”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get the pdf, put the first one in the foldier where are contained chapters’ directory and run the script.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second one is a launcher and need if you want to extract more pdf “togheter”. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bug-notes&quot;&gt;Bug Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a known GUI’s bug: it may happen that the update bars do not follow the download. Your download will be ok.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>/personal/2014/04/28/manga_downloader.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/personal/2014/04/28/manga_downloader.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Yelp Predictor</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;This is a university project develop for the challenge held in the course &lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.google.com/site/sistemiintelligentiperinternet/&quot;&gt;Sistemi Intelligenti per Internet&lt;/a&gt;. It was required the development of a tool that can predict the rate of a place diven by a particular user, using data provided by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yelp.com&quot;&gt;Yelp&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More detailed information about the project request can be found it &lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.google.com/site/sistemiintelligentiperinternet/challenge-a-a-2013-2014&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, while as regards the development see at this &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/pdf/presentazione_challenge.pdf&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; (both located in italian)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Contributors --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;tag_box list-unstyled list-inline&quot;&gt;
	  &lt;li&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-users fa-lg&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://v1ll0.github.io&quot;&gt;
				&lt;span&gt;Valerio Cestarelli&lt;/span&gt;
			&lt;/a&gt;
	  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
				<link>/university/2014/01/19/yelp_predictor.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/university/2014/01/19/yelp_predictor.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Netkit LabGenerator</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Netkit_LabGenerator is an unofficial automatic tool for &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.netkit.org/index.php/Main_Page&quot;&gt;Netkit&lt;/a&gt; use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project resulted from the desire to reduce the time of creation (and modification) of a simulated laboratory, during the university course &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dia.uniroma3.it/~impianti/HomePage12-13/index_irc.html&quot;&gt;Infrastrutture delle Reti di Calcolatori&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-use-it&quot;&gt;How to use it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project contain a detailed instructions in italian located in “istruzioni per l’uso.txt”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The script creates a simulated network by reading the contens of “configuration_lab.conf”, described by a precise syntax. The project contain a sample file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One written the configuration file, start “lab_generator.sh” and netkit later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To changes the lab description just clean the netkit’s files through “clean.sh”, edit the configuration file and repeat the procedure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The script does NOT have any form of intelligence, therefore it only create one sketch of the file “bgpd.conf”, wich requires modification.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
				<link>/personal/2014/01/04/netkit.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/personal/2014/01/04/netkit.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Twitter Sentiment Analysis</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;This project consists in creating a simple software tool that is able to classify and predict textual data, extrapolated from Twitter. Were considered 40183 tweet,divided between training-set (40000) and testing-set (183).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For semplicity, the tool stores the information in memory and was realized with K-NN as prediction algorithm. However it was implemented an interface “ClassificationAlgorithm” to allow any future changes to the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of this project is to understand not only the positivity/negativity associated with a sentence, but also the influence of the parts of the speech contained therein.
The tool extracts the most common measures in information retrival area, from which it was possible to extract data and charts below with a 3-NN instance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;ConfusionMatrix&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;TruthPositive&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;TruthNegative&lt;/td&gt; 
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;SystemPositive&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;100&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;43&lt;/td&gt; 
	&lt;/tr&gt;	
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;SystemNegative&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;32&lt;/td&gt; 
	&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Statistics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;error rate: 43.04371584699454 &lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;accuracy: 0.48 &lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;precision: 0.6993006993006993 &lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;recall: 0.9259259259259259 &lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;breack-even: 0.8126133126133126 &lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;f1-measure: 0.7968127490039841 &lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;fails Number: 51&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
	&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt; Positive Recap &lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/twitter_sentiment_analysis/recap_positive.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
	&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt; Negative Recap &lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/twitter_sentiment_analysis/recap_negative.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>/university/2013/10/20/twitter_sentiment_analysis.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/university/2013/10/20/twitter_sentiment_analysis.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Plasm.js Projects</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;During the course course of “Computational Graphic” I used &lt;a href=&quot;http://cvdlab.github.io/plasm.js/&quot;&gt;PlasmJS&lt;/a&gt;, a language based on JavaScript for 3D modeling.
These are some workes that I have done. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-4&quot;&gt;
		&lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/h4&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/plasm.js_projects/apple.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-3&quot;&gt;
		&lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Bender&lt;/h4&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/plasm.js_projects/bender.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-4&quot;&gt;
		&lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Tea Cup&lt;/h4&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/plasm.js_projects/tac_tea_pot_cup_render.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-4&quot;&gt;
		&lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Tea Pot&lt;/h4&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/plasm.js_projects/tac_tea_pot_render.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>/university/2013/07/20/plasm_js_projects.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/university/2013/07/20/plasm_js_projects.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Plasm.js Desktop Release</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;PlasmJS Desktop Release is an unofficial off-line installation for the PlasmJS Language, available only for Ubuntu (should work on all Debian release) and Mac OS X.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project resulted from the need to deploy code off-line during the university course “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dia.uniroma3.it/~paoluzzi/web/did/graficacomp/2014/index.html&quot;&gt;Computational Graphics&lt;/a&gt;”. Also have been introduced some functionality to optimized the code develpment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more info about PlasmJS can read &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cvdlab/plasm.js&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;features&quot;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The installation is realized by a Bash Scripts’ calls concatenation, and offers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt; 
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;develop in Plasm.js off-line&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;custemed APIs' set&lt;/b&gt;: can store a new personlized API into a &quot;setup.js&quot; file, that will load dinamically every time you run your code. The project contains a personal set of APIs wrote it during the course&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;integrates withSublime Text 2 and Google Chrome&lt;/b&gt;:provide a personalized build system. You can wrote your code and just press &quot;ctrl&quot; + &quot;b&quot; to run it into a Google Chrome's tab&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;provide a &lt;b&gt;bash command&lt;/b&gt; to launch the system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;installation&quot;&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select the right foldier according to the computer platform and run “install.sh”. If a new PlasmJS version is available run “update.sh”.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>/personal/2013/04/25/plasm.js.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/personal/2013/04/25/plasm.js.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
